Good afternoon everybody
大家下午好
Welcome good to see you as always
欢迎一如既往地见到你
Today we're going to learn about a important concept in computer science called virtual memory
今天我们将学习计算机科学中一个称为虚拟内存的重要概念
So consider a system that uses physical addressing
因此，请考虑使用物理寻址的系统
Right we've always idea about memory so far has been that it's a contiguous array of physical bytes
我们总是对内存有所了解，因为它是一个连续的物理字节数组
That we can access just by giving some an offset called an address
我们可以通过给出一些称为地址的偏移来访问
So in a system that uses physical addressing
所以在使用物理寻址的系统中
The CPU executes like say a move instruction
CPU执行就像移动指令一样
Which generates an effective address,the physical address
其中生成有效地址，物理地址
And this address is actually the offset of a byte in main memory so
而这个地址实际上是主存储器中一个字节的偏移量
You know here the CPU has generated a physical address of 4
你知道CPU在这里生成了4的物理地址
Since that address to the memory
从那个地址到内存
And then the memory fetches the word from at that address and then sends it back to the CPU
然后内存从该地址获取该字，然后将其发送回CPU
Now this is in fact the way that very simple microcontrollers work
实际上，这是非常简单的微控制器工作的方式
But it's not the way most systems work including your phones, your desktops,your servers
但这并不是大多数系统的工作方式，包括手机，台式机和服务器
These systems instead virtualize this main memory
这些系统反而虚拟化这个主存储器
Now the idea of virtualization is a very important one in computer science
现在，虚拟化的概念在计算机科学中是非常重要的
And it expands a lot of it applies to, a lot of areas of computer systems
它扩展了很多适用于计算机系统的很多领域
Now when you virtualize a resource
现在，当你虚拟化资源时
You present the user of that resource with some different kind of view of that resource
你向该资源的用户显示该资源的一些不同类型的视图
You present typically some kind of an abstraction or some kind of a different view of the resource
你通常会呈现某种抽象或某种不同的资源视图
And you do it by interposing on accesses to that resource
你可以通过插入对该资源的访问来实现
So in all cases there's some resource and you want to virtualize it
所以在所有情况下都有一些资源，你想要虚拟化它
And you do that by interpting or interposing on the accesses to that resource
你通过插入或插入对该资源的访问来实现这一点
Okay and then once you...we saw this when we created wrapper functions for like malloc
好的，然后一旦你...我们在为malloc创建包装器函数时看到了这一点
I will showing you inter positioning
我会告诉你inter interposition
The same technique is used to virtualize a resource
使用相同的技术来虚拟化资源
And once you've intercePTEd that access then you can deal with it any way you want
一旦你获得了访问权限，那么你就可以以任何你想要的方式处理它
So that's how you have sort of full power to change a person to change the view of that resource okay
这就是你如何有足够的力量改变一个人来改变那个资源的观点
So a good example you saw this when we looked at disks
所以当我们查看磁盘时，你看到了这个例子
And you know physically disk consists of cylinders tracks sectors platters surfaces
而且你知道物理磁盘由气缸轨道扇形盘表面组成
And to access a particular sector on of those disks
并访问这些磁盘上的特定扇区
You have to specify the cylinder and the track and the surface
你必须指定圆柱体，轨道和曲面
Okay but we saw that the view that disk controller is present is actually different
好的，但是我们看到磁盘控制器存在的视图实际上是不同的
It's a virtualized view of the disk
它是磁盘的虚拟化视图
And the controller instead presents to the kernel a view of the disk as a series of a sequence of logical blocks
而控制器则将内核视图作为一系列逻辑块提供给内核
And it presents that view by intercepting the requests from the kernel for I/O
它通过拦截来自内核的I / O请求来呈现该视图
And changing those logical block numbers that the kernel sends into the actual physical address
并将内核发送的逻辑块号更改为实际的物理地址
Ok so that's a very important example of virtualization in a system
好的，这是系统中虚拟化的一个非常重要的例子
Now the memory is that is a very....is a crucial resource in the system
现在内存是非常......是系统中的关键资源
And what we found is that it's useful to virtualize that memory resource
我们发现，虚拟化内存资源非常有用
Okay and the way this is done
好的以及这样做的方式
Remember before we virtually the disk by having the disk controller intercept request
通过磁盘控制器拦截请求记住我们之前的虚拟磁盘
In the case of the main memory resource
在主存储器资源的情况下
The requests are actually intercePTEd by a piece of hardware called the MMU the memory management unit
这些请求实际上是由一块称为MMU的内存管理单元的硬件intercePTEd
So the way this works is that the CPU executes an instruction
所以它的工作方式是CPU执行指令
Say it's a move instruction that generates some effect of address
说它是一个移动指令，产生一些地址的影响
So this is actually a virtual address
所以这实际上是一个虚拟地址
It's the CPU sends that address to the MMU
它是CPU将该地址发送给MMU
Which goes through a process called address translation which will study later today
这是一个称为地址转换的过程，将在今天晚些时候进行研究
And it converts that virtual address in this case 4100 into a physical address 4
并且它将该情况下的该虚拟地址4100转换为物理地址4
Which actually corresponds to the address of that the data object that we want
这实际上对应于我们想要的数据对象的地址
Ok so once the MMU translates the virtual address to a physical address
好的，一旦MMU将虚拟地址转换为物理地址
Then the memory will return the word at that address
然后内存将返回该地址的单词
So this...
所以这...
My wonder why in the world would you want to do this
我想知道为什么你想在世界上做这件事
Well it turns out there's all kinds of good reasons to virtualize the address space
事实证明，虚拟化地址空间有各种充分的理由
And so before I can explain those to you
所以在我向你解释这些之前
Let me just define a few terms
我来简单定义几个术语
So an address space is a set of addresses
所以地址空间是一组地址
Ok so an address spaces is a set
好的，所以地址空间是一组
Not of data bytes but of the addresses of those bytes
不是数据字节，而是那些字节的地址
And a linear address space is a content is a contiguous set of contiguous non-negative integers
并且线性地址空间是内容是连续的非负整数集合
Okay so just 0,1,2,3,4 and so on
好的，只有0,1,2,3,4等等
The virtual address space is a set of N=2^n virtual addresses a linear it's a linear address space
虚拟地址空间是一组N = 2 ^ n个虚拟地址，线性地是线性地址空间
And the physical address space is a set of M=2^m physical addresses ok
并且物理地址空间是一组M = 2 ^ m的物理地址ok
And so typically the virtual address space is usually much larger than the physical address space
因此，通常虚拟地址空间通常比物理地址空间大得多
Okay the physical address space corresponds to the amount of DRAM that you actually have in the system
好的，物理地址空间对应于系统中实际拥有的DRAM数量
The virtual address space is the same for all processes running on that system
对于在该系统上运行的所有进程，虚拟地址空间是相同的
Okay why do we want to implement virtual memory
好的，为什么我们要实现虚拟内存
Why do this,why do this level of indirection with the MMU
为什么这样，为什么这个级别的间接与MMU
Well there's really three big reasons so
那么真的有三个重要原因
The first is that virtual memory uses the DRAM as a cache for the actual data stored on disk
第一个是虚拟内存使用DRAM作为存储在磁盘上的实际数据的缓存
Okay so you can think of virtual memory as it as a DRAM cache for data stored on the disk
好的，你可以将虚拟内存视为存储在磁盘上的数据的DRAM缓存
And this allows us to use the memory much more efficiently
这使我们能够更有效地使用内存
Because we only need to cache items that are frequently used
因为我们只需要缓存经常使用的项目
Right just the same idea that we learned when we talked about caches and locality
正好与我们在讨论缓存和位置时学到的相同
So that's one thing we can use the memory much more efficiently by only using the portions of the virtual address space
因此，通过仅使用虚拟地址空间的部分，我们可以更有效地使用内存
By only actually storing the portions of the virtual address space in the physical memory
通过仅将虚拟地址空间的部分实际存储在物理存储器中
Okay the second thing is it greatly simplifies memory management
好的第二件事是它大大简化了内存管理
So we saw it every process has the same view right
所以我们看到它每个进程都有相同的观点
There's code loaded at code and data are always loaded at the same address
代码中加载了代码，数据总是在同一地址加载
The stack is at the top of the user visible address space
堆栈位于用户可见地址空间的顶部
So every process has the same similar-looking virtual address space
因此，每个进程都具有相同的相似外观的虚拟地址空间
But in actual in actuality that the memory that corresponds to those
但实际上实际上是那些对应的内存
Those addresses is actually scattered all over main memory
这些地址实际上分散在主存储器中
Okay so that's a really important benefit of virtual memory
好的，这是虚拟内存的一个非常重要的好处
And then finally it allows us to protect accesses
最后它允许我们保护访问
So remember we had to...
所以记住我们必须......
A process we saw that a process provides the separate address space
我们看到一个进程提供了单独的地址空间
That's protected from accesses by other processes
这可以防止其他进程访问
Okay so virtual memory allows us to create these separate protected private address spaces
好的，所以虚拟内存允许我们创建这些单独的受保护私有地址空间
Okay and so what we'll do today we'll look in more detail at these three ideas
好的，我们今天要做的是，我们将更详细地了解这三个想法
And then we'll go into the specifics of address translation
然后我们将详细介绍地址转换
So I'm going to...for the first part of this lecture
所以我要......本讲座的第一部分
We're going to talk about address translation just in kind of high-level terms
我们将以高级术语来谈论地址转换
But then we'll go into the details at the end you can see how it really works
但是接下来我们将详细介绍细节，你可以看到它是如何运作的
Okay so let's look at VM as a tool for caching
好的，让我们看看VM作为缓存工具
So conceptually you can think of your virtual memory as a sequence of bytes stored on disk
因此，从概念上讲，你可以将虚拟内存视为存储在磁盘上的字节序列
And then the contents of that virtual memory stored on disk are cached in DRAM
然后存储在磁盘上的虚拟内存的内容缓存在DRAM中
Okay so think of the the DRAM is a cache for this array of contiguous bytes stored on the disk
好的，所以想想DRAM是存储在磁盘上的这个连续字节数组的缓存
And just like any cache the data is broken up into blocks
就像任何缓存一样，数据被分解成块
Okay and then we have so... so here we have the...
好的，然后我们就这样......所以我们在这里......
And those blocks for virtual memory systems are called pages
虚拟内存系统的那些块称为页面
They're typically larger than much larger than the cache blocks
它们通常比缓存块大得多
That we that we study done
我们研究完成了
So for k bytes typically instead of the 64 bytes
所以对于k字节通常而不是64字节
Like that we learned about in when we studied cache memories
就像我们在研究缓存记忆时所学到的那样
So this virtual memory conceptually you can think of it as being a sequence of pages stored on the disk
因此，从概念上讲，这个虚拟内存可以将其视为存储在磁盘上的一系列页面
So called virtual pages
所谓的虚拟页面
And each of these pages will identify with a number so here's virtual page 0,virtual page 1
并且这些页面中的每一个都将标识一个数字，因此这里是虚拟页面0，虚拟页面1
And then a subset of those pages are stored in the physical memory, in the physical DRAM memory
然后，这些页面的子集存储在物理存储器中的物理DRAM存储器中
And then there's some mapping function
然后有一些映射功能
That tells us which pages have been cached
这告诉我们哪些页面已被缓存
Ok so in this case I've just shown a snapshot
好的，在这种情况下，我刚刚展示了一个快照
Where we have three virtual pages cached somewhere in DRAM
我们在DRAM中的某个地方缓存了三个虚拟页面
Okay and there's no relation between the virtual page number and the the physical page number that it's mapped to
好的，虚拟页码与它映射到的物理页码之间没有关系
Some of these pages are not cached so they're still stored on disk
其中一些页面未缓存，因此它们仍存储在磁盘上
So in this case VP2 is still stored on disk
所以在这种情况下，VP2仍然存储在磁盘上
And there's some pages which aren't even allocated,so they don't exist on the disk
并且有一些页面甚至没有分配，因此它们不存在于磁盘上
It's a way to think of that
这是一种思考方式
Right we really wouldn't want to store
对，我们真的不想存储
Every single page in address space with that's to the size to the 48th
地址空间中的每一页都是大小到第48位
We really wouldn't want to store all those on disk
我们真的不想将所有这些存储在磁盘上
So most of the address space is unallocated
因此大多数地址空间都是未分配的
Ok so we can just think of this,so this DRAM is just a cache
好的，我们可以想到这一点，所以这个DRAM只是一个缓存
But it has a much different organization
但它有一个非常不同的组织
Than the cache memories we studied earlier
比我们之前研究的缓存记忆
And the difference is driven by that the enormous miss penalty when you go from
而这种差异是由于你离开时的巨大失误惩罚所致
If you have a cache and DRAM the miss penalty would to fetch a data item from the disk is huge
如果你有一个缓存和DRAM，那么从磁盘中获取数据项的错失将是巨大的
So the design of this virtual memory cache is totally driven by this enormous miss penalty
因此，这个虚拟内存缓存的设计完全由这个巨大的未命中惩罚驱动
And so as a result that blocks are larger
因此，块越大
So remember we talked about that the block size is kind of a trade-off
所以请记住，我们谈到块大小是一种权衡
Between sort of useful getting used being able to usefully amortize the cost of fetching that block
在某种有用的使用之间能够有效地分摊获取该块的成本
Versus sort of consuming too much of this scarce cache space right
而且有点过多地消耗这个稀缺的缓存空间
So in this case our cache memories were 64 byte blocks
所以在这种情况下，我们的缓存存储器是64字节块
Virtual most virtual memory systems have like 4k byte blocks with an option to increase to 4 megabytes
虚拟大多数虚拟内存系统具有4k字节块，可选择增加到4兆字节
In the case of x86
在x86的情况下
And now this cash and other consequence of the enormous missed penalty is that
现在，这笔巨额罚款的现金和其他后果就是这样
You really want to have as large associativity as you can
你真的希望拥有尽可能大的关联性
Remember we saw with direct mapped cache is that were subject to these conflict misses
请记住，我们看到直接映射缓存是受到这些冲突未命中的影响
And and if you increase the associativity of the cache
并且，如果你增加缓存的关联性
You reduce the probability of those conflict misses
你可以减少这些冲突未命中的可能性
But you never completely eliminate them until you have a fully associative cache with just one set
但是，除非只有一组完全关联的缓存，否则你永远不会完全消除它们
Okay so in a virtual memory,in a virtual memory cache
好吧，在虚拟内存中，在虚拟内存缓存中
It's fully associative there's one set and each virtual page can go anywhere in the cache
它是完全关联的，有一组，每个虚拟页面可以在缓存中的任何位置
Okay so this requires a really complicated mapping function
好的，这需要一个非常复杂的映射功能
Somehow we're going to have to keep track of where all these cached pages are
不知何故，我们将不得不跟踪所有这些缓存页面的位置
And we can't really do a search that would be way too inexpensive
我们不能真正做一个太便宜的搜索
So you remember when we with a cache memory the hardware actually did a search within the set
所以你记得当我们使用高速缓冲存储器时，硬件实际上在集合中进行了搜索
A parallel search to find try to find a cache line
并行搜索以查找尝试查找缓存行
But with a software cache like this that that's not feasible
但是像这样的软件缓存那是不可行的
All right so somehow we're going to have to remember where these cached blocks are in this very large set
好吧，所以我们不得不记住这些缓存块在这个非常大的集合中的位置
And again because it's so expensive if you make a mistake
再次因为如果你犯了错误就太贵了
When you're trying to identify a victim page
当你尝试识别受害者页面时
If you make a mistake and you evict a page that then is referenced again in the near future
如果你犯了一个错误并且你驱逐了一个页面，那么在不久的将来会再次引用它
You pay a big price for it okay
你付出了很大的代价还可以
So virtual memory caches have much more sophisticated replacement algorithms than like simple lru that
因此，虚拟内存缓存具有比简单的lru更复杂的替换算法
That we saw with cache memories
我们看到了缓存记忆
Now they're these replacement algorithms are outside of the scope of this course
现在他们这些替换算法超出了本课程的范围
You'll learn about them and when you take OS
你将了解它们以及何时使用OS
But because it's in software we can afford to do very expensive replacement algorithms
但是因为它是软件，我们可以负担得起非常昂贵的替代算法
And we can take a long fairly relatively long time to execute the code for those algorithms
我们可能需要相当长的时间来执行这些算法的代码
Because any time we spend figuring out a victim block will be much less than the cost of making a mistake
因为任何时候我们花费计算受害者的阻力都会比制造错误的成本低得多
And paying the access time,the miss time,the miss penalty to to disk
并支付访问时间，未命中时间，错过罚款到磁盘
And then also as a result of virtual memory systems never use right through  just  it takes to one
然后，由于虚拟内存系统永远不会正确使用它只需一个
Right so they always use right back and they try to defer writing anything back to the disk as long as possible
对，所以他们总是使用右后卫，他们试图尽可能地推迟将任何东西写回磁盘
Alright now how do we keep track
好吧，现在我们如何跟踪
Somehow we have to keep track of this complicated cache and DRAM
不知何故，我们必须跟踪这个复杂的缓存和DRAM
And the data structure that keeps track of the location of the virtual pages
以及跟踪虚拟页面位置的数据结构
In memory is called the page table
在内存中称为页表
Now a page table is just a data structure in memory
现在页表只是内存中的数据结构
That the kernel maintains for as part of each process context
内核维护为每个进程上下文的一部分
Okay so every process has its own page table
好的，所以每个进程都有自己的页表
And it's just a...it's an array of so called page table entries or PTEs
它只是一个......它是一组所谓的页表条目或PTE
Where PTE k contains the physical address of physical page k in DRAM okay
其中PTE k包含DRAM中物理页面k的物理地址
So here's how it works there's this page table in DRAM
所以这就是它的工作原理DRAM中的这个页面表
There's virtual pages stored on disk
存储在磁盘上的虚拟页面
And then there's....and then there's physical
然后就是....然后就是身体上的
There's virtual pages stored in various physical pages in DRAM
存储在DRAM中的各种物理页面中的虚拟页面
And then the page table keeps track of where those are stored
然后页表跟踪存储的位置
So here we have a case this PTE 1 corresponds to virtual page 1
所以这里我们有一个案例，这个PTE 1对应虚拟页面1
And in this case it says that virtual page 1 is mapped into physical page 0
在这种情况下，它表示虚拟页面1被映射到物理页面0
Virtual page 2 is mapped into physical page 1 and so on
虚拟页面2映射到物理页面1，依此类推
Ok now some of these the pages that aren't in memory are stored on disks the allocated pages
好的，现在其中一些不在内存中的页面存储在已分配页面的磁盘上
And so for those pages the page table entry contains a pointer to the location of that that page on disk
因此，对于那些页面，页表条目包含指向该页面在磁盘上的位置的指针
So think of it as a logical block number where that page can be found on the disk
因此，将其视为逻辑块编号，可在磁盘上找到该页面
And then some of the pages are
然后是一些页面
Not allocated so there's a null entry in the page table
未分配，因此页表中有一个空条目
Now a page hit
现在一个页面命中
So this is just a cache right,so we have hits and misses
所以这只是一个缓存权限，所以我们有点击和未命中
So a page hit occurs when there's a reference to a word in the virtual address space
因此，当存在对虚拟地址空间中的单词的引用时，会发生页面命中
That's contained in a page that's cached in the DRAM
这包含在缓存在DRAM中的页面中
Okay so let's say that we have you know the CPU execute this and move instruction it generates a virtual address
好吧，让我们说我们让你知道CPU执行它并移动指令它生成一个虚拟地址
The MMU
MMU
Looks up in the page table and let's say this virtual address is somewhere within virtual page 2
在页面表中查找，假设此虚拟地址位于虚拟页面2中的某个位置
Okay so that the MMU looks up the page table entry number 2
好的，以便MMU查找页表条目号2
And it extracts the physical address of that of that virtual page 2
并且它提取该虚拟页面2的物理地址
Okay so that's a, so in this case
好的，所以这是一个，所以在这种情况下
In this case the page is in memory it's cached in memory
在这种情况下，页面在内存中，它被缓存在内存中
And so we have a hit
所以我们受到了打击
And now the memory can return that,can return that physical address to the MMU
现在内存可以返回，可以将该物理地址返回给MMU
Now a miss is a reference to a word that's not cashed in physical memory
现在，未命中是对未在物理内存中兑现的单词的引用
So in this case virtual page 0,1,2,3 is not cached in DRAM
因此，在这种情况下，虚拟页面0,1,2,3不会缓存在DRAM中
It's stored on the disk
它存储在磁盘上
So now that triggers an exception ok page fault exception
所以现在触发异常ok页面错误异常
In the hardware the hardware triggers the exception
在硬件中，硬件触发异常
And that causes the transfer of control to a chunk of code in the kernel called the page fault handler
这导致控制转移到内核中称为页面错误处理程序的一大块代码
Which then selects a victim to be evicted,in this case virtual page 4
然后选择要驱逐的受害者，在这种情况下是虚拟页面4
And it fetches virtual page 3 from the disk
它从磁盘中获取虚拟页面3
Loads it up into memory
将其加载到内存中
And if and then changes,and then updates this page table entry to reflect the fact that virtual page 4 is now stored on disk
然后更改，然后更新此页表条目以反映虚拟页面4现在存储在磁盘上的事实
And if virtual page 4 had been modified at any time it would have to write the contents of it that to disk as well
如果虚拟页面4在任何时候都被修改过，那么它也必须将它的内容写入磁盘
So once the handler is copied virtual page 3 into memory
因此，一旦处理程序将虚拟页面3复制到内存中
The instruction that caused the page fault now can be re-executed
现在可以重新执行导致页面错误的指令
Okay so once the...so when the page fault handler in the kernel returns it returns to the faulting instruction
好的，所以一旦......所以当内核中的页面错误处理程序返回时，它返回到错误指令
Which then reacts acutes
然后反应急剧
And now that page is when the MMU checks that the PTE corresponding to that page
现在该页面是MMU检查对应于该页面的PTE的时候
It finds that it's indeed cache so
它发现它确实缓存了
So now the instruction can continue and we can fetch that
所以现在指令可以继续，我们可以获取它
Whatever word at that virtual address from the DRAM
无论来自DRAM的虚拟地址是什么字
Okay now we can allocate a new page of memories
好的，现在我们可以分配一个新的记忆页面
So in this example virtual page 0,1,2,3,4,5 is not allocated
因此，在此示例中，未分配虚拟页面0,1,2,3,4,5
So if you need to let's say you do malloc of a very large chunk of virtual address space
所以，如果你需要让你说你做了一大块虚拟地址空间的malloc
If those pages,if one of those pages hasn't been allocated yet then the kernel actually
如果这些页面，如果尚未分配其中一个页面，那么实际上是内核
Or the malloc function actually has to create allocate that memory by calling a function called s break
或者malloc函数实际上必须通过调用一个名为s break的函数来创建分配该内存
Okay and then what s break does is actually allocates
好吧，然后休息的确实是分配
This page and records where it's loaded now would probably actually put it up into
这个页面和记录它现在加载的位置实际上可能会把它放入
Now I guess it wouldn't actually show up in the DRAM cache until it was that page was touched
现在我猜它实际上不会显示在DRAM缓存中，直到触摸该页面为止
Okay so just allocating space just changes this page table entry
好的，只需分配空间只需更改此页表条目即可
And then when that page is actually touched then it'll be brought into the cache
然后当实际触摸该页面时，它将被带入缓存
So I don't know about you but the first time I learned about this I was
所以我不了解你，但我第一次了解到这一点
I was pretty appalled it just seemed like the most inefficient terrible idea right
我非常震惊，它似乎是最低效的可怕想法
How in the world can you afford to on every single instruction that uses memory
对于使用内存的每一条指令，你在世界上怎么能负担得起
Do all this copying back and forth and looking up in tables
做所有这些来回复制并查阅表格
And it just seems like an awful idea
这似乎是一个糟糕的主意
But once again locality saves us
但是地方再次拯救了我们
Okay and it actually works because programs have locality
好吧，它确实有效，因为程序有地方性
Okay and it's actually fairly efficient
好的，它实际上相当有效
And the reason is that at any point of time programs tend to access a set of pages called the working set
原因是在任何时候程序都倾向于访问一组称为工作集的页面
Okay just by locality right by temporal locality,by the principle of temporal locality and spatial locality
通过时间局部性，时间局部性和空间局部性原则，仅仅通过局部性
You tend to sort of reuse the same things reuse nearby things okay
你往往会重复使用相同的东西重复使用附近的东西
And so if that working set is less than the main memory size
因此，如果该工作集小于主存储器大小
Then all of the pages in the current were that will fit in memory and then things will be great
然后当前的所有页面都适合内存，然后事情就会很好
Okay but if the some of the working set sizes for for every process right our systems running multiple processes
好的但是如果每个流程的一些工作集大小使我们的系统运行多个流程
If it exceeds the main memory size
如果超过主内存大小
Then you have this meltdown where processes are thrashing each other and causing pages to be copied back and forth
然后你就会发生这样的崩溃，其中进程互相颠簸并导致页面来回复制
So you never ever know process ever gets it's working set fully into memory
因此，你永远不会知道进程将其工作集完全放入内存中
Okay and we'll look at a technique when we look at address translation
好的，当我们查看地址转换时，我们会看一下这种技术
We'll look at a little hardware cache called a translation look aside buffer
我们将看一个称为转换后备缓冲区的小硬件缓存
That further exploits the locality property of programs
这进一步利用了程序的局部性
Okay so that's virtual memory is a tool for caching
好吧，这样虚拟内存就是一种缓存工具
It's also a member of tool for memory management
它也是内存管理工具的一员
And it greatly simplifies all kinds of aspects of memory management for the kernel
它极大地简化了内核的各种内存管理方面
So the key idea is that each process has its own virtual address space
所以关键的想法是每个进程都有自己的虚拟地址空间
The kernel implements this by giving each process its own separate page table
内核通过为每个进程提供自己独立的页表来实现这一点
In the context of that process so it's just a data structure in the kernel
在该过程的上下文中，它只是内核中的数据结构
That the process key...that the kernel keeps for that process
内核为该进程保留的进程密钥
And the page table for each process maps the virtual address space for that process
每个进程的页表都映射该进程的虚拟地址空间
Now what's interesting so you have that these pages contiguous pages in the virtual address space
现在有趣的是让你在虚拟地址空间中拥有这些页面连续的页面
Can be mapped anywhere in the DRAM,in the physical address space
可以映射到DRAM中的任何位置，在物理地址空间中
So and they can be scattered all over the place
所以他们可以分散在各处
And different virtual pages and different processes can be mapped to different physical pages
并且可以将不同的虚拟页面和不同的进程映射到不同的物理页面
So here we have virtual page one which is mapped to physical page two
所以这里我们有虚拟页面1映射到物理页面2
In process 1 but in process 2 virtual page one is mapped to physical page 8
在过程1中，但在过程2中，虚拟页面1被映射到物理页面8
Okay so in this way we can present a view to each,to the programmer and to the tools
好的，通过这种方式，我们可以为每个人，程序员和工具提供一个视图
That each process has a very similar address space virtual address space
每个进程都有一个非常相似的地址空间虚拟地址空间
Same size address space code and data start at the same place
相同大小的地址空间代码和数据从同一个地方开始
But then the actual pages that process used can be scattered in memory
但随后处理的实际页面可能会分散在内存中
Okay and then it gives us the most efficient way to use the memory
好的，然后它为我们提供了使用内存的最有效方式
If we didn't have this mechanism think about how would you keep track let's say you had 50 processes running
如果我们没有这个机制，请考虑如何跟踪让我们说你有50个进程在运行
On the machine at any point in time
在任何时间点的机器上
How in the world would you keep track of where all of the the data  those processes were using
如何在世界上跟踪这些进程使用的所有数据的位置
Well one technique that you could imagine in fact it was used in the in the bad old days but before virtual memory
那么你可以想象的一种技术实际上它是在过去的糟糕时期但在虚拟内存之前使用的
One thing you can imagine is that just give every process its own chunk of the physical address space
你可以想象的一件事是，只需为每个进程提供物理地址空间的一部分
Just take your physical address space partition it
只需将你的物理地址空间分区即可
And then each process gets loads and runs and it's own part of the address space
然后每个进程都获得加载和运行，它是地址空间的一部分
Well this has all kinds of problems right I mean you could
嗯这有各种各样的问题，我的意思是你可以
If you what do you do if you add a process
如果你添加了一个过程，你会怎么做
So you really can't partition the address space you really have to sort of say well
所以你真的无法对你真正需要的地址空间进行分区
Each process gets some little chunk
每个进程都有一些小块
And I'm going to reserve some of the address space in case there's new processes that need memory
而且我会保留一些地址空间，以防新的进程需要内存
Another problem is that now you have to write your programs
另一个问题是，现在你必须编写你的程序
You can't just link your program ahead of time
你不能提前链接你的计划
Because it has to be relocated when it's loaded right
因为它必须在正确加载时重新定位
Because you don't...you know a process, you don't know where in the memory it's going to go, it's going to get some chunk
因为你没有......你知道一个过程，你不知道它将会在内存中去哪里，它会得到一些大块
So you have to either relocate all the the references
所以你必须要重新定位所有的引用
That the references to global symbols at when it's actually loaded
在实际加载时引用全局符号
Or you have to create a system where all of the instructions are relative
或者你必须创建一个所有指令都是相对的系统
So there's no absolute addresses
所以没有绝对的地址
All addresses are relative to say the start of the program something like that
所有地址都相对于程序的开头而言就是这样
So anyway all of these things are just terribly complicated
所以，无论如何，所有这些事情都非常复杂
And they're all solved beautifully by virtual memory
它们都被虚拟内存完美地解决了
So the each virtual page can be mapped to any physical page so that really helps simplify things
因此，每个虚拟页面都可以映射到任何物理页面，这样可以真正帮助简化操作
And even at different times the same virtual page can be stored in different physical pages at different times
甚至在不同时间，相同的虚拟页面可以在不同的时间存储在不同的物理页面中
All right so if a page for it,for a while it might be cached in one physical page
好吧，如果它是一个页面，有一段时间可能会缓存在一个物理页面中
Then it gets swapped out and the next time it's referenced
然后它被换出并在下次引用时
It can get cached in a different physical page that if it's no longer available
如果它不再可用，它可以缓存在不同的物理页面中
Right so it provides so the most flexible scheduling freedom
对，因此它提供了最灵活的调度自由度
In the way that we in...the way that we manage the memory
以我们处理记忆的方式
And it also provides this really neat capability
它还提供了这种非常巧妙的功能
Where you can map virtual pages to the same physical page
你可以在哪里将虚拟页面映射到同一物理页面
So there's this is a very simple straightforward way for multiple processes to share certain code or data
因此，对于多个进程共享某些代码或数据，这是一种非常简单的直接方式
Okay and what you do is you just that the page table entry in these different processes
好的，你所做的只是这些不同进程中的页表条目
Just points to the same physical page
只需指向相同的物理页面即可
So in this case virtual page 2 points to physical page 6
因此，在这种情况下，虚拟页面2指向物理页面6
In each of the page tables for process 1 and process 2
在流程1和流程2的每个页面表中
So this is how shared libraries are implemented
这就是共享库的实现方式
Right so lib.c is the same code for every process running on the system
对，所以lib.c与系统上运行的每个进程的代码相同
So lib.c just needs to be loaded once into physical into physical memory
所以lib.c只需要一次加载到物理内存中
And then processes that want to access functions and data in lib.c just map
然后想要访问lib.c中的函数和数据的进程只是映射
The pages in their virtual address space to the physical pages where lib.c is actually loaded
虚拟地址空间中的页面指向实际加载lib.c的物理页面
Ok so now there's only one copy of lib.c everywhere in the system
好的，现在系统中只有一个lib.c的副本
But every process thinks it's got its own copy
但每个过程都认为它有自己的副本
Now this virtual memory for...
现在这个虚拟内存...
Using virtual memory to help simplify memory management greatly simplifies linking and loading
使用虚拟内存来帮助简化内存管理可以大大简化链接和加载
Ok for the reasons I mentioned before
好的，我之前提到的原因
Linkers now can assume that every program is going to be loaded at exactly the same place
Linkers现在可以假设每个程序都将在完全相同的位置加载
So the linker knows ahead of time where everything is going to be
所以链接器提前知道所有内容将会是什么
And then it can resolve it can relocate all those references accordingly
然后它可以解决它可以相应地重新定位所有这些引用
Now it really makes loading as simple
现在它确实使加载变得简单
So what...so execve the loader
那么...所以...执行加载器
If you want to load a program now execve looks at the elf binary the executable binary
如果要加载程序，现在execve查看elf二进制文件的可执行二进制文件
Ok it sees how it identifies how big the code and the data sections in that binary are
好吧，它看到它如何识别该二进制文件中的代码和数据部分有多大
It allocates virtual memory starting at a fixed address for the code and data
它从代码和数据的固定地址开始分配虚拟内存
It creates PTEs for them and marks each of them is invalid
它为它们创建PTE并标记它们中的每一个都是无效的
Ok so each PTE contains a valid mapping
好的，所以每个PTE都包含一个有效的映射
So each PTE that's mapped to code and data contains a valid physical page number
因此，映射到代码和数据的每个PTE都包含有效的物理页码
But then the it does this trick of setting the valid bit to 0
但是它确实将有效位设置为0
So when the MMU x encounters a PTE whose valid bit is 0
因此，当MMU x遇到有效位为0的PTE时
It triggers a page fault
它会触发页面错误
Right it looks as though that page is not been initialized yet
看起来好像该页面尚未初始化
So it's kind of a trick
所以这是一个伎俩
Right and then that triggers a page fault to the kernel
正确然后触发内核的页面错误
And then the kernel will then can then copy that that page into physical memory
然后内核可以将该页面复制到物理内存中
Ok so this the loading actually programs and data aren't actually they're not low loaded
好的，这样加载实际上程序和数据实际上并不是它们没有低负载
You know they're not just like copied into memory
你知道他们不只是像复制到记忆中一样
It happens as a result of of page faults,it happens as a result of misses
它是由于页面错误而发生的，它是由于未命中而发生的
When and it's deferred to until a byte in that page is accessed
什么时候推迟到该页面中的一个字节被访问
Okay so this is called demand paging okay
好的，所以这叫做需求分页好吧
But it's really just like any of the other caches we've looked at right
但它真的就像我们看到的任何其他缓存一样
You don't load a block into the cache until a word within that block is accessed okay
你不会将块加载到缓存中，直到该块中的单词被访问为止
So loading actually...so loading is actually this is a very efficient mechanism right because
所以实际加载...所以加载实际上这是一个非常有效的机制，因为
You may have a program that contains a huge,say a huge array,a large array
你可能有一个程序包含一个巨大的阵列，一个巨大的阵列，一个大阵列
But you're only accessing a portion of that array
但是你只是访问该数组的一部分
So that entire array won't actually be be allocated the pages will only come into DRAM
因此，实际上不会分配整个阵列，页面只会进入DRAM
When they're...when a word within that page is touched
当他们......当触摸该页面中的某个单词时
So if you're only accessing a portion of this extremely large array
所以如果你只是访问这个极大数组的一部分
Only the data that you access gets loaded and used
只有你访问的数据才会被加载和使用
So it's a very very smart mechanism and extremely helpful for
所以这是一个非常非常聪明的机制，非常有用
For allowing us to use this precious memory resource
允许我们使用这种宝贵的内存资源
Okay so the third motivation for virtual memory is that it helps us protect portions of memory
好吧，虚拟内存的第三个动机是它可以帮助我们保护内存的一部分
So you recall that our processes
所以你记得我们的流程
You know portions of our virtual address space or read-only like the code section
你知道我们的虚拟地址空间的一部分或只是代码部分的只读
Okay and there are other portions of the address space that can only be executed by the kernel
好的，地址空间的其他部分只能由内核执行
So on...
所以......
On systems like x86-64
在像x86-64这样的系统上
It's a 64-bit system
这是一个64位系统
So the pointers and addresses or 64 bits
所以指针和地址或64位
But in actuality the real virtual address space is 48 bits
但实际上，真正的虚拟地址空间是48位
Okay so it's only..it's 2^48
好的，所以它只是..这是2 ^ 48
And then the high-order bits after bit 48 are either all zeros or all ones
然后，位48之后的高位比特全部为零或全部为1
Okay so
可以，然后呢
And that's the that sort of intel's rule
这就是那种英特尔的规则
And so the addresses where the high order bits are all ones are reserved for the kernel
因此，高位比特都是1的地址是为内核保留的
The kernels code and the kernels data
内核代码和内核数据
Okay the addresses were all the bits are zero or reserved for user code
好的地址是所有位都为零或保留用户代码
Okay so any reference,any address that contains all ones in those higher order bits
好的任何引用，包含那些更高阶位的所有地址的任何地址
Is by definition either code or data in the kernel
根据定义，内核中的代码或数据
And so you can add bits to the PTE
因此你可以向PTE添加位
That specify whether certain virtual pages can be accessed by user code
这指定了用户代码是否可以访问某些虚拟页面
Or if they have to be accessed by the kernel,so this so-called supervisor mode
或者如果它们必须由内核访问，那么这就是所谓的管理员模式
And you can also add bits that control whether that page can be read written or executed
你还可以添加控制该页面是否可以读取或执行的位
Okay so this executes bit is new with x86-64,it didn't exist in 32-bit x86 systems
好的，所以这个执行位是x86-64的新功能，它在32位x86系统中不存在
And this is the technique that's used now to try to prevent against attack lab code injection style attacks
这是现在用来试图防止攻击实验室代码注入风格攻击的技术
Because it makes it impossible
因为它使它变得不可能
If this bit is set you can't load instructions from any byte within that page
如果设置此位，则无法从该页面中的任何字节加载指令
And so in fact it was this the introduction of this execute bit
事实上，正是这个引入了这个执行位
That's or led to things like return-oriented programming attacks like you did in your attack lab
这或者像你在攻击实验室那样导致了面向回归的编程攻击
Okay so this by just the simple technique of adding bits to the PTE
好的，这只是通过向PTE添加位的简单技术
We provide a way attic way to protect
我们提供了一种阁楼保护方式
Different parts of our virtual address space from unauthorized accesses
我们的虚拟地址空间的不同部分来自未经授权的访问
And then the the MMU actually checks these bits on each access
然后MMU实际上在每次访问时检查这些位
And if there's a problem you know if you're trying to do a right and the right
如果有问题，你知道你是否正在努力做正确的事
The right that's not enabled then it throws an exception which then the kernel the colonel deals with
没有启用的权限然后它抛出一个异常，然后是上校处理的内核
Ok so so far I've been talking about address translation it kind of high-level terms
好吧到目前为止我一直在讨论地址翻译这种高级术语
So let's get down to details and see how it really works
所以让我们深入了解细节，看看它是如何运作的
Okay so we're given a virtual address of N elements physical address of M elements
好的，我们给出了M个元素的N个元素物理地址的虚拟地址
Like I said before N is usually larger than M but it doesn't have to be
就像我之前说的那样，N通常比M大，但并非如此
Okay it's perfectly there's no reason M could be much larger than N
好吧，这完全没有理由M可能比N大得多
And there it's typically not but it could be
它通常不是，但它可能是
And so given these two address spaces we have a map function that takes that maps from V to P
因此，给定这两个地址空间，我们有一个map函数，可以将映射从V映射到P.
With an optional empty set or with an additional empty set
使用可选的空集或附加的空集
And so for virtual address a,MAP(a)=a'
对于虚拟地址a，MAP（a）= a'
If the data at virtual address a is a physical address a'
如果虚拟地址a处的数据是物理地址a'
Okay so I mean that's just what we...it's just a little more formal way to say
好的，所以我的意思是，这就是我们......这只是一种更正式的说法
What we've been talking about before with our diagrams
我们之前用图表谈过的是什么
And then map a is the empty set if the data at virtual address a is not in physical memory
如果虚拟地址a处的数据不在物理内存中，则映射a为空集
Okay so just for a summary I'm going to put up a list of all the symbols we're going to be using in address translation
好的，只是为了总结我将列出我们将在地址转换中使用的所有符号
But this is just for summary,this is just for reference if you're using the slides later on
但这只是为了总结，如果你稍后使用幻灯片，这仅供参考
Okay so here's how address translation where the page table works
好的，这就是页面表工作的地址转换方式
So we're given some virtual address
所以我们给了一些虚拟地址
That consists of n bits
它由n位组成
And we have blocks that consists of whose size can be represented with p bits
我们有块，其大小可以用p位表示
Okay so think about this now there
好的，现在想想这个
So this is very similar to what we looked at when we did caching you know the address bits for a cache
因此，这与我们在进行缓存时所看到的非常类似，你知道缓存的地址位
So these first p bits correspond to the page offset
所以这些前p位对应于页面偏移
So this is analogous to the blocks offsets that we saw with caches
所以这类似于我们在缓存中看到的块偏移量
And then the remaining bits correspond to the virtual page number
然后剩余的位对应于虚拟页码
This is so member this is fully associative right so there's only one set
这是成员，这是完全关联的权利所以只有一组
So in a fully associative cache everything after the block offset is tagged
因此，在完全关联的缓存中，标记了块偏移之后的所有内容
So think of this as like a tag
所以把它想象成一个标签
This is the...this is what uniquely identifies this block
这是...这是唯一标识此块的内容
And we in virtual memory parlance we refer to it as a virtual page number
我们在虚拟内存的说法中将它称为虚拟页码
Now the page table the beginning of the page table is pointed to by this page table based register
现在页面表的页面表的开头是由这个基于页面表的寄存器指向的
On intel systems  that's it's called CR3 control register 3
在英特尔系统上，它被称为CR3控制寄存器3
But this register contains the physical address of the page table in memory
但是该寄存器包含内存中页表的物理地址
The beginning of that...
那个开始......
And so when the when the CPU presents a virtual page,a virtual address to the MMU
因此，当CPU呈现虚拟页面时，MMU的虚拟地址
It takes the virtual page number
它需要虚拟页码
And uses that as an index into the page table
并将其用作页表的索引
Ok and then it...and that identifies a page table entry which contains if this is mapped into memory
好然后它......它标识一个页表条目，其中包含是否映射到内存中
I contains the physical address of the corresponding physical page
我包含相应物理页面的物理地址
Ok so the whole purpose of address translation is to come up you're given a virtual address
好吧，地址转换的全部目的是为了给你一个虚拟地址
And you want to come up with a corresponding physical address
而你想要提出一个相应的物理地址
Ok so the physical address,the physical page number portion of the physical address comes out of the page table entry
确定物理地址，物理地址的物理页码部分来自页表条目
And this is interesting the the physical page offset portion of the physical address comes out of the virtual page offset
有趣的是，物理地址的物理页面偏移部分来自虚拟页面偏移
And it those bits are identical
而那些位是相同的
Okay so now you should convince yourself that this is true right
好的，现在你应该说服自己这是对的
The offset in a virtual block is going to be the same as the offset in a physical block
虚拟块中的偏移量将与物理块中的偏移量相同
They're the same size blocks
它们的大小相同
And you can also see why this virtual page number
而且你也可以看到为什么这个虚拟页码
It identifies the page number in the page table
它标识页表中的页码
So imagine a virtual address that's all zeros
所以想象一下全部为零的虚拟地址
Okay all zeros
好吧全是零
So it's virtual address zero
所以它的虚拟地址为零
And now that will have a virtual page number of zero
现在，虚拟页面数将为零
And the byte at that address will be at offset zero
并且该地址处的字节将在偏移零处
Okay now increment by one virtual address one
好的，现在增加一个虚拟地址
So that will be in an offset of 1 and it will be in the same virtual page of zero
因此，它将在1的偏移量中，并且它将在零的相同虚拟页面中
Right now keep incrementing until all of the bits in the virtual page offset are ones
现在继续递增，直到虚拟页面偏移中的所有位都是1
And the virtual page numbers is zero
虚拟页码为零
Okay so this is the last byte in that virtual page zero
好的，这是该虚拟页面零的最后一个字节
Now increment one more time
现在再增加一次
The one bit carries over to the virtual page number so now we go to the next virtual page
一位继承到虚拟页码，现在我们转到下一个虚拟页面
And it's at an offset of zero okay so
它的偏移量为零，所以
So can you see it's sort of sort of obvious when you think about it like that
所以，当你这么想的时候，你能看到它有点明显吗？
You know why we can just take these bits after the virtual page offset and use them to uniquely identify
你知道为什么我们可以在虚拟页面偏移之后获取这些位并使用它们进行唯一标识
What virtual page were we're working with
我们正在使用什么虚拟页面
Okay so let's see how I
好的，让我们看看我是怎么回事
Let's see how it works in this system in more detail
让我们更详细地了解它在该系统中的工作原理
So our system our CPU sends a virtual address to the MMU as a result of executing
因此，我们的系统CPU会在执行结果时向MMU发送虚拟地址
A move instruction or call or return or any kind of control transfer
移动指令或呼叫或返回或任何类型的控制转移
The MMU
MMU
Looks up the PTE, so it fetches the PTE from the page cable stored in memory
查找PTE，因此它从存储在内存中的页面电缆中获取PTE
So this is actually going off the chip onto memory into this PTE stored in memory
所以这实际上是将芯片从存储器中移入存储在存储器中的PTE中
It gets the it fetches the PTE extracts the and uses that PTE to construct the physical address
它获取PTE提取并使用该PTE构造物理地址
Okay and then it sends that physical address to the cache and memory system
好的，然后它将该物理地址发送到缓存和内存系统
Which eventually results in the data being returned back to the CPU
这最终会导致数据返回到CPU
Okay so even for a hit,we still have memory references
好的，即使是热门，我们仍然有内存参考
Right because we have to fetch that page table entry
是的，因为我们必须获取该页表项
Now miss is in this parlance is called a page fault
现在想念就是这个用语被称为页面错误
So in this case the same thing happens as before that the CPU sends the virtual address to the MMU
因此，在这种情况下，同样的事情发生在CPU之前将虚拟地址发送到MMU
The MMU fetches that the PTE for memory
MMU获取PTE作为内存
But then when it looks then when the MMU looks at the PTE
但是当它看起来然后当MMU看PTE时
It sees that there's either an invalid valid bit or a zero valid bit or the
它看到有无效的有效位或零有效位或
The it's indicated that the data stored on disk
它表明数据存储在磁盘上
And so in that case it the MMU triggers a page fault exception
因此，在这种情况下，MMU会触发页面错误异常
Which transfers control to this page fault handler
将控制转移到此页面错误处理程序
The handler identifies a victim and
处理程序识别受害者和
If it's been modified copies it out to disk
如果已被修改，则将其复制到磁盘
Then it fetches the new page from disk into memory and up through the cache hierarchy
然后，它将新页面从磁盘提取到内存中，然后通过缓存层次结构
OK
好
And then it did...
然后它确实......
And then it causes that the then the handler returns to the to the process
然后它导致然后处理程序返回到进程
And when a handler for a fault returns
并且当故障的处理程序返回时
It causes the faulting instruction to re-execute
它导致错误指令重新执行
So now the move instruction that faulted is re-execute,but this time there's a page hit
所以现在出现故障的移动指令会重新执行，但这次有一个页面命中
Now you may be interested how the cash is integrated into all of this
现在你可能会对现金如何融入所有这些感兴趣
So the MMU send fetches page table entries
因此MMU发送提取页表条目
So it passes page table addresses to the cash
所以它将页面表地址传递给现金
If those missed those go to memory
如果那些错过那些去记忆
The memory returns those page table entries to the cache
内存将这些页表条目返回到缓存
And then ultimately to the MMU
然后最终到了MMU
The MMU constructs that physical address and then its sense that physical address to the cache
MMU构造该物理地址，然后将其感知到物理地址到缓存
Right so with caching the way we've been caching is done using physical addresses
正确地使用物理地址来缓存我们已经缓存的方式
Okay in this case it's also possible to construct caches that work with virtual addresses but yes
好的，在这种情况下，也可以构建使用虚拟地址的缓存，但是
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Yeah so, it will get into that...
是的，它会进入......
Okay so the question is how is the virtual address space implemented on disk
好的，问题是如何在磁盘上实现虚拟地址空间
And it when it actually does a much more efficient thing than the sort of a abstract model that I described
它实际上比我描述的那种抽象模型更有效
So most pages there's an option when you allocate a new virtual memory page
因此，当你分配新的虚拟内存页面时，大多数页面都有一个选项
You can allocate it,so that it's all zeros
你可以分配它，所以它都是零
Okay so there's a special you can say I want this I want to allocate a page of all zeros
好的，所以有一个特殊的你可以说我想要这个我想要分配一个全零的页面
In that case you know that page doesn't need to ever get stored on disk
在这种情况下，你知道该页面不需要存储在磁盘上
Right it's just the memory it's as though it was created on disk and then loaded into memory
它只是内存，就好像它是在磁盘上创建然后加载到内存中一样
So those pages that are all zeros don't exist on disk
因此，磁盘上不存在全零的页面
You know when pages are modified
你知道何时修改页面
It's a little more pages can be mapped to particular files for example when we load an elf binary
例如，当我们加载elf二进制文件时，可以将更多页面映射到特定文件
The pages that correspond to the code are actually mapped to the bytes in the binary
与代码对应的页面实际上映射到二进制文件中的字节
That contain the code
那包含代码
So that when you miss on that page it fed it brings in those code pages
所以，当你错过了那个页面时，它会输入它带来的那些代码页
Okay so pages can be mapped to user level files on disk
好的，所以页面可以映射到磁盘上的用户级文件
Or not they can be anonymous and not mapped
或者不是他们可以匿名而不是映射
So if they're mapped to user level
因此，如果他们被映射到用户级别
If they're mapped to user level files and you write to a page
如果它们映射到用户级文件并且你写入页面
Then it will get written back to the page that it's mapped to
然后它将被写回到它映射到的页面
If it's not mapped to any page it's stored in this area called the swap area or the swap file okay
如果它没有映射到任何页面，它存储在这个称为交换区域或交换文件的区域中
yes
是
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Oh yeah so the question is when you load a page from disk into memory
哦是的所以问题是当你从磁盘加载一个页面到内存
Does it also get cached in the cache memory hierarchy and the answer is yes
它是否也缓存在缓存内存层次结构中，答案是肯定的
So if you load an entire page
因此，如果你加载整个页面
That page will be broken up into blocks 64 byte blocks
该页面将被分成64字节块
And and load it into the cache
并将其加载到缓存中
So everything that you fetch from the cache goes through
因此，你从缓存中获取的所有内容都会通过
The from the memory goes through the cache hierarchy
内存中的内容通过缓存层次结构
Okay so I claim that virtual memory works
好的，所以我声称虚拟内存有效
Because of locality and that's true but if we still had to fetch
因为地方性，这是真的，但如果我们仍然需要取
If every time we had a miss we still had to go to memory
如果我们每次怀念，我们仍然需要记忆
It would be too inefficient
效率太低了
Okay so the the MMU speeds up this translation process by caching page table entries
好吧，MMU通过缓存页表条目来加速这个翻译过程
In a hardware cache within the MMU called the translation look aside buffer or TLB
在MMU内的硬件缓存中，称为转换后备缓冲区或TLB
So the TLB is a hardware cache that caches is PTEs page table entries
因此TLB是一个硬件缓存，缓存是PTE页表条目
And it contains like it contains a cache of the most recently
它包含它包含最近的缓存
You know it's just like any other cache so it contains a cache of the most recently used page table entries
你知道它就像任何其他缓存一样，因此它包含最近使用的页表条目的缓存
And so the the MMU remember the the unique part of a virtual address that defines a virtual page is the virtual page number bits
因此，MMU记住定义虚拟页面的虚拟地址的唯一部分是虚拟页面编号位
Okay so the the the TLB uses the the VPN portion of the virtual address  to access it
好的，TLB使用虚拟地址的VPN部分来访问它
And so that just like any other set it has a set index a set of set index bits which are just determined by how many
因此，就像任何其他集合一样，它有一个集合索引，一组设置的索引位，它们只取决于多少
How many entries that or how many sets that the TLB has
TLB具有多少个条目或多少个条目
And it has a tag with for the remaining bits to disambiguate any and to disambiguate any cash lines or PTEs
并且它有一个标记，其余位用于消除歧义，并消除任何现金线或PTE的歧义
The map to the same set
地图到同一套
Okay so the the VON or the TLBI(TLB index) maps to this particular set
好的，所以VON或TLBI（TLB索引）映射到这个特定的集合
And then it uses the...
然后它使用...
The TLB uses the TLBT bits to disambiguate and determine if the PTE that it's looking for is,it is really stored in the cache
TLB使用TLBT位消除歧义并确定它正在寻找的PTE是否真的存储在缓存中
Okay so the way this works is
好的，这样做的方式是
CPU generates a virtual address it goes through the MMU
CPU生成一个通过MMU的虚拟地址
The MMU instead of looking in memory and directly going to the page table entry
MMU而不是查看内存并直接转到页表条目
It first asks the TLB if it has that it sends it the VPN
它首先询问TLB是否有将其发送给VPN的情况
And so do you have this virtual page the PTE for this virtual page
那么这个虚拟页面是否为此虚拟页面的PTE
And if it does the TLB returns a hit
如果确实如此，则TLB返回命中
And it returns that page table entry which the MMU can then use to construct the physical address
然后它返回MMU可用于构造物理地址的页表条目
To send to the cache and memory system
发送到缓存和内存系统
Eventually I result in that the data being sent back
最终我导致数据被发回
Now when you have a miss then there's this one the MMU checks with the TLB for the PTE
现在，当你有一个未命中时，MMU会检查这个PTB的TLB
It misses so then the MMU has to go to memory just like before okay so this is
它错过了，所以MMU必须像以前一样去记忆，所以这是
And then everything is the same the memory returns the PTE to the MMU which stashes it in the TLB
然后一切都是相同的，内存将PTE返回到MMU，并将其存储在TLB中
And just like before if there's no room in the
就像以前一样，如果没有空间的话
If yeah if a PTE has been modified then it has to be written back out okay just like any other cache
如果是的话，如果PTE已被修改，则必须将其写回，就像任何其他缓存一样
And eventually the MMU uses that to construct a physical address and then the data gets sent back
最终，MMU使用它来构建物理地址，然后将数据发回
Okay if you've been paying attention unlike a couple people
好吧，如果你一直在注意不像一对人
If you've been paying attention
如果你一直在关注
You're going to be very concerned about the size of these page tables
你将非常关注这些页表的大小
Right that I mean
对，我的意思是
We've got 4kbytes suppose we have 4kbytes pages
我们有4千字节，假设我们有4千字节的页面
And our effective address space is 48 bits like it is with an x86-64 system
我们的有效地址空间是48位，就像使用x86-64系统一样
Then and we have an 8-byte page table entry
然后，我们有一个8字节的页表条目
We need a page table 512 gigabytes
我们需要一个512千兆字节的页表
Okay the address space 2^48 bytes
好的地址空间2 ^ 48个字节
Divided by 2^12 bytes per page
每页除以2 ^ 12个字节
Okay so that's the number of page table entries that we need
好的，这就是我们需要的页表条目数
And then the size of each page table entry is 8 bytes
然后每个页表项的大小为8个字节
So we need almost a terabyte of of DRAM just to hold the page table right so
因此，我们需要几乎1TB的DRAM来保持页面表的正确性
So then obviously it's not going to work
那么显然它不会起作用
And it's obviously not how their page tables are really implemented
而且显然不是他们的页表真正实现的方式
So the solution is to to use a hierarchy of page tables
所以解决方案是使用页表的层次结构
So in it so we if we have a two level page table
所以在我们这里，如果我们有一个两级页表
The there's a top of first level page table called the level 1 table
第一级页面表的顶部称为级别1表
Which is always in memory ok it's never never page down
这总是在记忆中确定它永远不会丢失
And then there's a suit a sequence of level 2 page tables and they're all the same size
然后就是一套2级页面表的序列，它们的大小都相同
Right and the first level 1 table points to the beginning of the first level 2 table
右侧和第一级1表指向第一级2表的开头
So it contains a physical address that points to the base
因此它包含指向基础的物理地址
The second level 1 table points to the second level 2 table and so on okay
第二级1表指向第二级2表，依此类推
So if we have this kind of system remember most of the virtual address space is unused
因此，如果我们有这种系统，请记住大部分虚拟地址空间未使用
Right so if we have this kind of system we can avoid creating many unnecessary page tables
是的，如果我们有这种系统，我们可以避免创建许多不必要的页表
Okay so imagine if we have a two level hierarchy
好的，想象一下，如果我们有一个两级层次结构
So let's look at our virtual address space in this example
所以让我们看一下这个例子中的虚拟地址空间
And what I've allocated two k pages for code and data for this program
我为这个程序分配了两个k页的代码和数据
And then there's their 6k unallocated pages
然后是他们的6k未分配页面
And then the stack then there's a page that's allocated for the stack
然后堆栈然后有一个分配给堆栈的页面
I'm sorry there's a thousand 24 pages allocated for the stack
对不起，这个堆栈分配了24个页面
Most of which are...I'm sorry...there's a region of memory that
其中大部分都是......我很抱歉......有一个记忆区域
That's the size of a thousand 24 pages
这是一个24页的大小
But most of them are unallocated and I've only allocated one for the top of the stack
但是大多数都是未分配的，我只为堆栈顶部分配了一个
Okay so given this layout for my process
好的，所以给我的过程这个布局
I only need three level to page tables
我只需要三个级别的页面表
Okay the first page table covers this region of my code and data
好的，第一页表格涵盖了我的代码和数据的这个区域
The first thousand 24 pages
第一千页24页
The next page table covers the remaining thousand 24 pages
下一页表格涵盖剩余的一千二十四页
Okay so these two level two page tables cover all of the code and data
好的，所以这两个二级页表涵盖了所有的代码和数据
Okay and similarly the what I need for my stack I just need one page table
好吧，类似我需要的堆栈我只需要一个页面表
And it only has one valid PTE it's the very last one
它只有一个有效的PTE，这是最后一个
Okay and then I have a single level one table that points to the three level two tables
好的，然后我有一个单一的表，指向三个二级表
Okay so I've...with four page tables I've covered the entire virtual address space
好的，所以我...有四个页面表我已经覆盖了整个虚拟地址空间
Now the way that the MMU uses these multiple page tables to do address translation is as follows
现在，MMU使用这些多页表进行地址转换的方式如下
Again we have a virtual page offset which consists of the first p bit
我们再次有一个虚拟页面偏移量，它由第一个p位组成
And then the VPN the remaining bits give the VPN
然后VPN剩下的比特给VPN
For a k level page table are broken up into k sub vpns
对于k级页面表被分解为k个子vpns
Okay and each is the same size
好的，每个都是相同的大小
And so now in this system the upper VPN one which consists of the uppermost bits of the VPN
现在在这个系统中，上层VPN由VPN的最高位组成
Are an offset into the level 1 table
是1级表的偏移量
Which is as before is pointed to by the page table base register
页表基址寄存器指向的是前面的内容
Okay so VPN1 is the index into the level 1 page table
好的，所以VPN1是1级页面表的索引
Remember the level 1 page table points to the address of the level 2
请记住，1级页面表指向级别2的地址
That are an entry a PTE in the level 1 table
这是1级表中的PTE条目
Points to the address of some level 2 page table
指向某个2级页面表的地址
Or it contains the address of some level 2 page table
或者它包含某些2级页表的地址
So that points to the base of this level 2 page table
所以指向这个2级页面表的基础
And then the vpn 2 bits are used as an index into that level 2 table right and so on
然后将vpn 2位用作该2级表的索引，依此类推
Ok so eventually you get at the a PTE and the level k-1 table
好吧，所以最终你得到了一个PTE和k-1级表
Points to the beginning of the level k page table
指向级别k页面表的开头
And VPN k points to an offset within that table
VPN k指向该表中的偏移量
Which finally contains the physical address of the page that we want to access
最后包含我们要访问的页面的物理地址
Okay and then that physical address is used to form the PPN portion of the physical address
好的，然后该物理地址用于形成物理地址的PPN部分
And just like before the virtual page offset is just copied directly unchanged to the physical page offset
就像之前虚拟页面偏移直接复制一样，直接复制到物理页面偏移量
So is that clear to everybody
所有人都清楚这一点
Yes question
是的问题
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Let's see is it always a power of two yes
让我们看看它总是两个是的力量
At least and it's defined by the architecture,so for intel it's a four level system
至少它是由架构定义的，因此对于intel来说它是一个四级系统
Now why would it be and then the quick could it will...it always be less than 6
现在为什么会这样，然后它会快速...它总是小于6
Oh give us a 64-bit system yeah
哦，给我们一个64位系统是啊
Yeah there's only the block size is fixed
是的，只有块大小是固定的
Right so that there's 12 bits here 2^12 is 4k
正确，这里有12位，2 ^ 12是4k
So the remaining it's that you actually have 48 bits to play with
所以剩下的就是你实际上有48位可以玩
So the remaining 48 bits could that's right so if it was 4 if it was 8  it would be 6 so you're right
所以剩下的48位可能是正确的，如果它是4，如果它是8那么它将是6所以你是对的
In this scheme it could be at most 6 turns out in practice it's set at 4
在这个方案中，它实际上最多可以是6转，它设置为4
And there was a question over here
这里有一个问题
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Have it like this multi-level system
有它像这个多级系统
Oh okay so the question
哦好的，所以问题
Is yeah the question is how does it save you space
是的问题是它是如何为你节省空间的
So the reason it saves you space is you go back to this other figure maybe I didn't explain this well enough
所以它为你节省空间的原因是你回到这个其他的数字，也许我没有解释得这么好
So you see this
所以你看到了这个
If we...okay so let's say we wanted to map this virtual address space with a single page table
如果我们......好吧那就让我们说我们想用一个页面表来映射这个虚拟地址空间
We would need a PTE for every page within that address
我们需要为该地址内的每个页面提供PTE
Whether it was used or not
是否使用过
Okay it goes back if we had a 48-bit address space
好吧，如果我们有一个48位的地址空间，它会回来
We'd need enough,we need a page table entry for each page virtual page in that address space
我们需要足够的，我们需要在该地址空间中的每个页面虚拟页面的页表条目
Okay whether that page was used or not,so let me think about it 2^48 is a x several exabytes
好的，不管是否使用过这个页面，让我想一想2 ^ 48是x几个exabytes
We need a page table that would have an entry for each virtual page
我们需要一个页表，每个虚拟页面都有一个条目
In that to the 48th bit address space
在那到第48位地址空间
And most of those pages by far the vast majority would never ever be used
到目前为止，大多数这些页面绝大多数都不会被使用
Okay so that's where the waste comes in
好的，这就是垃圾进来的地方
Okay so here with a multi-level page system with this multi-level scheme
好的，这里有一个多级页面系统，这个多级方案
You only need to generate in this case these level two if it's a two-level system
如果是两级系统，你只需要在这种情况下生成这两级
You only need to generate level two page tables
你只需要生成二级页表
Enough level two pages to cover the portion of the virtual address space that you're actually using
足够的两级页面来覆盖你实际使用的虚拟地址空间部分
Okay and that portion of the virtual address space that you're not using at this gap right here
好的，你在这个空白处没有使用的那部分虚拟地址空间就在这里
There's no need to have a page table is
没有必要有一个页表
Is that clear?that that's a really good important question,but you look unconvinced
那是否清楚？这是一个非常重要的问题，但你看起来并不相信
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Well yeah yeah you still need you still need a page table that has
好吧是的是的你仍然需要你仍然需要一个页面表
Let's see in this case there's 4k bite pages 4 bit PTE
让我们看看在这种情况下有4k咬页4位PTE
So there's 1k you have 1k PTEs
所以有1k你有1k PTE
So you still need you still need a level 1 page table that has 1k PTEs
因此，你仍然需要一个具有1k PTE的1级页表
But those are only 8 bytes right I mean
但是我的意思是那些只有8个字节
So you still need to you still need to have space
所以你仍然需要你还需要空间
Because you don't know you know you're not sure which of these which reason of the address space you're going to need to cover
因为你不知道你知道你不确定这些地址空间的哪个原因需要覆盖
Ok and it's the same thing for
好的，这是一回事
Here in this case, in these first two PTEs these first two level 2 page tables
在这种情况下，在前两个PTE中，前两个2级页表
They're portion of the address space was actually all being used
它们是地址空间的一部分实际上都在使用
Right so each one of these PTEs at level 2 had to be allocated had to be initialized and used
正确，因此必须分配第2级的这些PTE中的每一个必须被初始化和使用
Right but in this portion of the address space that contain the stack
正确但是在包含堆栈的地址空间的这一部分中
This third level 2 page table has most of its PTEs or no
这个第三级2页表有大部分的PTE或没有
You still have to allocate space for them but they're there no
你仍然需要为他们分配空间，但他们没有
Ok that's a really good question it's important that I hope that's clear
好的，这是一个非常好的问题，重要的是我希望这一点很清楚
Any other questions will we go on
我们会继续提出任何其他问题
Sorry oh okay question
对不起，好的问题
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Exactly just
完全正确
Just like here the MMU members doing all of this this is all hardware logic
就像这里MMU成员所做的一切都是硬件逻辑
So it and the art the number of page tables levels is defined by the architecture okay
所以它和艺术的页面表级别的数量是由架构定义好的
So the MMU takes the virtual address that's presented to it
因此，MMU获取呈现给它的虚拟地址
And it uses a portion a subset of those bits to access each page table okay
并且它使用这些位的子集的一部分来访问每个页表
So it's just like...did I answer your question?okay
所以就像......我回答你的问题了吗？好的
So it's just like before that
所以就像那之前一样
The level k,VPN k is used to compute an index into the level k page table yes
级别k，VPN k用于计算级别k页表中的索引是
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Okay the question is why are the indices arranged right to left on which diagram
好的问题是为什么索引从右到左排列在哪个图表上
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Oh these are the bits,this is the least significant bit it's always bit zero
哦，这些是位，这是最不重要的位，它总是位为零
Yeah that's a good question,so the question was why do these
是的，这是一个很好的问题，所以问题是为什么这些
In this diagram why are these these bits labeled right to left starting at zero
在此图中，为什么这些位从零开始从右到左标记
And the answer is that we're indicating the bit position
答案是我们正在指出比特位置
So zero is the least significant bit and n-1 is the most significant bit
因此，零是最低有效位，n-1是最高有效位
Yes question
是的问题
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Yeah so the question is what's the overhead involved in these when you have these multiple levels
是的，所以问题是当你有这些多个级别时，这些开销涉及到什么
Now are you talking about overhead to
现在你在谈论开销
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Yeah well so there's clearly if you don't get TLB hits
是的，所以如果你没有获得TLB点击，那就很明显了
It would be a lot of overhead
这将是一个很大的开销
Because it would be you would be fetching PTEs from multiple page tables for memory
因为你将从多个页表中获取内存中的PTE
So that but because of locality the chances are almost the...
所以，但由于地方的原因，机会几乎是......
The chances this level one table covers the entire address space
这一级表覆盖整个地址空间的可能性很大
So it's always going to be in the in the PTE, in the TLB
所以它总是会出现在PTE中的TLB中
These level two tables are covering a huge swath of the address space
这两级表覆盖了大量的地址空间
So chances are they're going to be in the TLB too right so
所以他们很有可能在TLB中也是如此
So as long as your program has reasonable locality
所以只要你的程序有合理的位置
Most of these lookups are going to hit in the TLB
大多数这些查找都会在TLB中出现
Okay so it turns out that the overhead with reasonably written programs is negligible
好的，事实证明合理编写程序的开销可以忽略不计
But that's a very it's a very important consideration
但这是一个非常重要的考虑因素
You know maybe that's maybe that speaks against increasing at some point if you had too many page tables
你知道，如果你有太多的页表，也许这可能会反对在某些方面增加
You might increase the probability of misses in the TLB
你可能会增加TLB中未命中的可能性
So it's probably something they very carefully considered
所以这可能是他们非常仔细考虑的事情
Okay any other questions yeah
好的，还有其他任何问题
[student speaking]Yeah so if we use segmentation plus paging,so it is the addresses page table the recommended linear address of our real
[学生说话]是的，如果我们使用分段加分页，那么地址页表就是我们真实的推荐线性地址
Ho boy the question was how does segmentation fit into this and
何男孩的问题是分割如何适应这个和
We're not going to go there
我们不会去那里
So in earlier intel systems
所以在早期的英特尔系统
Such as the actually the first intel system I programs it was a 286
比如实际上我编程的第一个英特尔系统是286
So the 286 no is neat it was the 8086
所以286没有它是8086的整洁
Anyway in earlier intel systems had 16-bit addresses
无论如何，在早期的英特尔系统中有16位地址
Which is tiny right
哪个很小
It's only 2^16 for your address space
你的地址空间只有2 ^ 16
And so as a hack to try to increase the effective size of the
因此，作为一个黑客，试图增加有效的大小
Of this address space the introduced the notion of segmentation
在这个地址空间中引入了分割的概念
And so there were four segments 4-bit
所以有四个4位段
There was a register segment registers that contain 4 bits that could be applied to the address
寄存器段寄存器包含4位可应用于该地址的寄存器
So an address was the combination of the segment knows more than
所以一个地址是段的组合知道更多
Yeah you need the segment formed
是的，你需要形成的部分
The address then was a combination of the segment bits plus the address
然后地址是段位加地址的组合
So you could use the segment bits to create an offset
因此，你可以使用段位来创建偏移量
So it was a - it wasn't effectively a 20 bit address space
所以它是 - 它实际上不是一个20位的地址空间
But you can only address,you can only access it in 2^16 chunks right so the
但你只能解决，你只能在2 ^ 16块中访问它，所以
The segment would determine an offset into the that this 20-bit address space
该段将确定该20位地址空间的偏移量
And then from that you could address 16 bits
然后从那里你可以解决16位
So it was this very unsatisfying devilishly hard to program thing because
因此，这是非常令人不满意的非常难以编程的事情
You can only access 16 bit chunks at a time
你一次只能访问16位块
So anyway we're not going to a few years later they came to their senses and just created a real virtual memory system with linear drill spaces
所以无论如何我们不会在几年后他们开始意识到他们只是创建了一个带有线性钻孔空间的真实虚拟内存系统
But you know really there
但你知道的确如此
Yeah I don't know we're just did
是的我不知道我们刚才做到了
I'm not even sure if they do address translation on those actually
我甚至不确定他们是否确实解决了这些问题
So I'm not sure but you really don't want to go there
所以我不确定，但你真的不想去那里
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Yeah oh it does it does so the question is it doesn't exist anymore
是的哦它确实如此，问题是它不再存在了
Everything intel's been incredibly good about maintaining backward compatibility
英特尔在保持向后兼容性方面一直非常出色
So that stuff's all in there
那些东西都在那里
But there's a mode bit when you boot your system up you set a bit that says I want a linear address space
但是当你启动系统时有一个模式位，你设置了一点我想要一个线性地址空间
Okay any other question
还有其他任何问题
Oh no VPN to is the offset
哦没有VPN是抵消
Okay so the question is why do we care about VPN2 since that it points to the level 2 table
好吧，问题是为什么我们关心VPN2，因为它指向2级表
So what gives you the beginning of the level 2 table is the PTE entry in the level 1 table
那么为你提供2级表开头的是1级表中的PTE条目
Okay so the level 1 table points to the beginning of that level 2 table
好的，所以1级表指向该2级表的开头
And VPN to gives you the offset into that the level 2 table
并且VPN为你提供了2级表的偏移量
So the it finds the address by taking the base address
所以它通过取基地址找到地址
And then VPN2 times the PTE sighs
然后VPN2倍PTE叹息
Okay good good any other questions
好的，还有其他任何问题
Okay well that'll do it for today
好的，那就是为今天做的
Next week or on Thursday we'll look at
下周或周四我们会看一下
How how virtual memory is implemented in real systems and in Linux
虚拟内存如何在实际系​​统和Linux中实现